Wolf, William B. Audio-Visual 6305 AV
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
William B. Wolf Audio-Visual
1978-2000
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Wolf, William B.
6305 AV
15.22 cubic feet
14.2 linear ft.
Oral histories, audiovisual material.
This is a collection of Oral Histories done by William B. Wolf and recorded on cassette and VHS tapes.
7000089
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, April 16, 2013
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, August 31, 2015
Biographical / Historical
Arbitrator, labor mediator and attorney; visiting professor, New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations, Cornell University. Wolf served as permanent arbitrator between the New York City Board of Education and the United Federation of Teachers; New York City and the American Federation of State, County, and Municipal Employees (AFSCME); the New York City Off-Track Betting Corp. and AFSCME; New York State and AFSCME; the State University of New York and the Senate Professional Association; A. Goodman and the American Bakery and Confectionery Workers' Union; and between the Simmons Company and the Upholsterers International Union. Wolf also served as impartial chairman for American Airlines and the Transport Workers Union of America; the men's shirt industry and the Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America; and the Brooklyn Union Gas Company and the Transport Workers Union of America.
Born May 6, 1909. Attended Cornell University (B.A. 1930; LL.B. 1932).
Formerly labor mediator, New York State Board of Meidation; labor relations examiner, N.Y.S. Labor Relations Board.
Affiliated with National Academy of Arbitrators (board of governors 1971-; regional chairman 1967-1968); Industrial Relations Research Association; Society for Professionals in Dispute Resolution; New York Bar Association. On rosters of American Arbitration Association, Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service, National Mediation Board, New York State Board of Mediation, New Jersey State Board of Mediation, New York Public Employment Relations Board, New Jersey Public Employment Relations Commission.
Arbitrator under contract for N.Y. City Board of Education and UFT; City of New York and District Council 37; OTB and DC37; N.Y. State and Council 82, AFSCME: State University of New York and Senate Professional Association; Metropolitan New York Milk Industry and IBT; New Rochelle Board of Education and UFT; A. Goodman amp; Sons and BCWU; Metropolitan Association of Optical Wholesalers and IUE; Simons Co. and Local 420, UIU.
Impartial Chairman; American Airlines and TWU, Men's Shirt Industry and ACWA; Brooklyn Union Gas and TWU; Williams Press and Pressmen's Union; Hiring Hall amp; Club Employees Union (Local 16); Westchester County Laundry Board of Trade and Local 335 IBT: Rochdale Village, Inc. and Local 90 Public Service Union; Ossining Board of Education and Ossining Teachers Association; Schwartz Laboratories, Inc. and Oil, Chemical and Atomic Workers; Ross Oil Term. Corp., Howard Fuel Corp. amp; Local 365 UAW.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5305: Benjamin H. Wolf Papers 5477: Benjamin Wolf Papers 5511: Benjamin Wolf Additional Papers 5539: Benjamin H. Wolf Additional Arbitration Files 5803: Benjamin Wolf Additional Arbitration Files 6305: William B. Wolf Papers 6305 P: William B. Wolf Photographs
Oral histories; Personnel management; Organizational behavior; Job stress; Motivation (Psychology); Barnard, Chester Irving, 1886-1961; Bradford, Lee; Brewington, Anne; Dubin, Bob; Fass, Lyn; Gardener, Burleigh; Goetz, Billy; Greenwood, Ron; Henessey, John; Kahn, Earl; Krieger, Joe; Levy, Sid; Lewy, Hans; Massarik, Fred; Moore, Dave; Peterson, Ross; Sang, Luikin; Senn, Larry; Simon, Herbert; Voris, William; Whyte, William Foote, 1914-2000; Wolf, William B.; Worthy, James C.; Council of Foreign Economics of Taishan (Kwangtung); New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations; University of Chicago. School of Business
7000089
- William F. Whyte - Interview with W.B. Wolf - 12/12/1978, 1 (Box 4)
  Scope and Contents
  tape 1
- William F. Whyte - Interview with W.B. Wolf - 12/12/1978, 2 (Box 4)
  tape II
- Bill Whyte Interview with W.B. Wolf - 12/12/1978, 3 (Box 4)
- James Worthy - 10/12/1991, 1 (Box 5)
  tape 2
- James Worthy - 10/21/1991, 1 (Box 6)
  tape I
- Jim Worthy - Symposium - 5/2/1991, 1 (Box 7)
- Hamada Anthro Studies of Organization - 10/2/1992, 1 (Box 8)
- Jim Worthy - 8/10/1992 -- Las Vegas, 1 (Box 9)
- Worthy, Moore, Gardner -- Committee on HR in Industry -- 8/1986, Chicago, 1 (Box 10)
  tape III
- Burleigh Gardner - 5/9/1980, 1 (Box 11)
- Harriet Moore - I - 3/17/1992, 1 (Box 12)
- Harriet Moore II - 3/17/1992, 1 (Box 13)
- Chicago Headquarters - Jack London -- 12/2/1984, 1 (Box 14)
- Bob Dubin amp; Bill Wolf - Discussion of the Univ. of Chicago, 1 (Box 15)
- Bob Dubin - Univ. of Chicago - 1990, 1 (Box 16)
- Chas. Henry - 7/31/1992, 1 (Box 17)
- Earl Kahn - Applied Behavioral Science - 12/29/1991, 1 (Box 18)
  Tape I of II
- Whyte by Student Lyn Fass - 12/5/1972, 1 (Box 19)
- Whyte - by Lyn Fass -- 12/2/1972, 1 (Box 20)
  Tape II
- Sidney Levy - 3/10/1992, 1 (Box 21)
- Sid Levy - 10/12/1992, 1 (Box 22)
- Sid Levy - II - 3/2/1992, 1 (Box 23)
- Dave Moore amp; Burleigh Gardner - Committee on HR in Industry, 1986; 1 (Box 24)
- James Worthy amp; W.B. Wolf - tape IV - 10/21/1991, 1 (Box 25)
- James Worthy amp; W.B. Wolf - 10/19/1991, 1 (Box 26)
- Sid Levy - 3/19/1992, 1 (Box 27)
- William Whyte - Interview by W. Wolf, 1 (Box 28)
- Whyte - tape 2, 1 (Box 29)
- Hamada - Applied Anthro - 10/2/1992, 1 (Box 30)
- Earl Kahn - SRI Applied Behavioral Science -- 12/29/1991, 1 (Box 31)
- Billy Goetz, 1 (Box 31)
- Fred Massarik - 7/6/1972 - Sensitivity Training, 1 (Box 32)
- Classes in Development of Mgt., 1989; 1 (Box 32)
  8/14/1989 -- Copy 2
- Whyte - 6/10/1970, 1 (Box 33)
- Oral Hist. Univ. of Chicago School of Business - Anne Brewington amp; William B. Wolf - 1989, 1 (Box 33)
- Billy Goetz, 1 (Box 34)
- Bill Whyte - 6/27/1970, 1 (Box 34)
  III
- Herbert Simon, Karl Wrek, Burleigh Gardener, Jim Worthy, Bill Wolf, Bill Whyte -- 8/13/1986, 1 (Box 35)
- William Whyte - 11/2/1992, 1 (Box 36)
- Academy of Mgt. - 8/10/1979, 1 (Box 41)
- W.B. Wolf - 8/14/1989 - Reflect. Of Hist. of Mgt., 1 (Box 42)
- Academy - Cumming - J.C. Penny, 1 (Box 43)
- Interview of Bateson amp; Mead -- Re: Macy Conferences - Read by Students, 1 (Box 44)
- 10-9-1991 -- Interview with Dave Moore, 1 (Box 45)
- 6/25/1984Senn - 6/30/2000, 1 (Box 46)
  copy I
- Professor Mano - 3/29/1979, 1 (Box 47)
- Professor Voris - 01/09/1992, 1 (Box 48)
- 5/31/1971 -- Session, 1 (Box 49)
- Academy of Mgt. Annual meeting - 8/14/1989, 1 (Box 50)
- Charles Wrege - Phone Conversation - 7/4/1994, 1 (Box 51)
- Mary Cushing Nite, 1 (Box 52)
- Roundtree - 10/24/1972, 1 (Box 53)
- History of Mgt., 1 (Box 54)
- 3/3/1985 - Mayo Rountree, 1 (Box 55)
- 10/17/1972, 1 (Box 56)
- October 10, 1 (Box 57)
  #3
- October 10, 1 (Box 58)
  #1
- 3/3/1984 - Elton Mayo, 1 (Box 59)
- Mary Parker Fillett - 10/3/1972, 1 (Box 60)
- Mary Parker Fallett - 10/3/1972, 1 (Box 61)
- 10/17/1972, 1 (Box 62)
- Lyn Urwick - 11/28/1972, 1 (Box 63)
- Whyte - Lyn Fass, 1 (Box 64)
- Pete Drucker, 1 (Box 65)
- 10/10/1972, 1 (Box 66)
- 10/17/1972, 1 (Box 67)
- A. Rowntree - 3/3/1984, 1 (Box 68)
- Peter Drucker - 11/21/1972, 1 (Box 69)
- 3/4/1984, 1 (Box 70)
- 9/12/1972, 1 (Box 71)
- Wolf Lecture - 9/12/1972, 1 (Box 72)
- Rountree - 10/24/1972, 1 (Box 73)
- 9/26/1972, 1 (Box 74)
- China Hotel - 10/30/1980, 1 (Box 75)
- Interviewer - 9/24/1980, 1 (Box 76)
- Lee Bradford - 1966, 1 (Box 77)
- Ross Peterson (2nd Casey) - Reading of W.B.W. amp; Steve Wolf - Sept. 1988, 1 (Box 78)
- Herbert Simon - ASDA Meeting - 7/28/1997, Philadelphia, 1 (Box 79)
- Hans Levy amp; Bill Wolf - 1986, 1 (Box 80)
- William B. Wolf-The Water Lite Co. - told to students in Univ. of Wash. Class - 1/16/1990, 1 (Box 81)
- Larry Senn - 6/30/2000, 1 (Box 82)
- Larry Senn Interview by B. Wolf - 6/30/2000, 1 (Box 83)
- Academy of Mgt. - Meeting - 8/20/1994, 1 (Box 84)
- Session I - 1/25/1979 -- ILR 690, 1 (Box 85)
- Hawaii - Music, 1 (Box 86)
- Unlabeled, 1 (Box 87)
- 2/28/1974, 1 (Box 88)
  only labeling on tape
- John Henessey - Re: t-groups in NW 1996 or 1997, 1 (Box 89)
- Interview with Chester I. Barnard by William B. Wolf: April 1961, 1 (Box 90)
- Excerpt - Henderson 1961, 1 (Box 91)
  handwritten label very difficult to read
- How Barnard came to write the (?), 1 (Box 92)
- 4/5/1961 (Chester I. Barnard), 1 (Box 93)
  handwriting on tape very hard to read
- 4/6/1961 (Chester I. Barnard), 1 (Box 94)
  handwriting on cassette very difficult to read
- Prof. J. Karino, 1 (Box 95)
- Wm. B. Wolf: Reflections of Chester I. Barnard: April 1961, 1 (Box 96)
- Excerpts from CIB tapes, 1 (Box 97)
- Barnard Excerpts, 1 (Box 98)
- Barnard Excerpts - non-logical, 1 (Box 99)
- Open System Re-Design, 1 (Box 100)
- Improving International Relations and Effectiveness within Multinational Organizations, 1 (Box 101)
  case is empty
- The Client as Theorist: An Approach to Individual amp; Org. Development, 1 (Box 102)
- A "Mixed Model" Strategy for Changing Medical Centers, 1 (Box 103)
- Reducing Job Stress Related to coronary Heart Disease: A Pilot Org. Development Project, 1 (Box 104)
- Training in autonomy and initiative, 1 (Box 105)
- OD in a Macrosystem--A Three Year Progress Report, 1 (Box 106)
- Motivation, Organization Development amp; Individual Career Achievement, 1 (Box 107)
- OD in large systems, 1 (Box 108)
- Lecture 5, 1 (Box 109)
- Lecture 4, Part 2, 1 (Box 110)
- Lecture 4, Part 1, 1 (Box 111)
- Lecture 3, Part 2, 1 (Box 112)
- Lecture 3, Part 1, 1 (Box 113)
- Lecture 2, 1 (Box 114)
- Lecture 12, 1 (Box 115)
- Lecture 11, 1 (Box 116)
- Lecture 10, Part 2, 1 (Box 117)
- Lecture 9, Part 2, 1 (Box 118)
- Chen ? - Part Sec. for Factory (?), 1 (Box 119)
  Handwriting on tape is hard to read
- Taishan Chemical Factory, 1 (Box 120)
- The Council of Foreign Economic of Taishan (Kwangtung) - Liu Kin Sang -- 11/8/1985, 1 (Box 121)
- Taishan County Machinery Electrical Appliances, 1 (Box 122)
- Yentel, 1 (Box 123)
- Garden Hotel - 11/20/1985, 1 (Box 124)
- Balyon Hotel - 11/28/1985, 1 (Box 125)
- Garden Hotel, 1 (Box 126)
- Bayon Hotel -- 11/28/1985, 1 (Box 127)
- China Hotel - 10/30/1985, 1 (Box 128)
- Lecture 8, Part 1, 1 (Box 129)